I'm a UI/UX designer with an extensive background in graphic and interior design. I have experience in social media marketing and have 3+ years in management experience. I recently completed an online bootcamp studying UI/UX design and strive for a clean and intuitive user experience with a minimalistic, yet visually striking interface.

PROJECTS

You in Review

UI/UX Designer | February 2020 - March 2020

- Developed an interactive lifestyle tracker that helps the user stay on track and keep good habits.
- Designed an aesthetically pleasing interface to present to-do list, data, and insights based on color.
- Conducted research to determine motivating factors to help ensure continuous use of mobile application.

The Wander Project

UI/UX Designer | May 2019 - August 2019

- Reimagined a cloud storage project that changes the way a user would make itineraries for traveling.
- Designed a responsive website with mobile application capabilites.
- Researched and performed usability testing to best integrate social media qualities to a cloud storage application.

EXPERIENCE

Jim T. Nguyen Law

UI/UX Designer (Freelance) | May 2020 - Present

- Redesigned website for prospective clients for a more intuitive human experience.
- Developed code for website and enhanced device responsiveness.
- Created style guide to unify website and (my) previous work to further develop a professional brand.

Graphic Designer (Freelance) | February 2019

- Designed logo and brand for a business's graphic needs (ie: letter heads, signage, business cards, etc).
- Iterated and finalized business cards for print.

365 Staging

Lead Designer | April 2017 - May 2019 Graphic Designer | January 2018 - May 2019

- Directed a small team to prepare residential homes to be listed on the real estate marketplace.
- Curated pieces of furniture and accessories to coordinate with the architectural style of the home.
- Created graphic design content such as decals, posters, and flyers for company and real estate use.

Togos

Social Media Marketing Designer | May 2017 - June 2018

- Managed Instagram account by posting content and communicating with customers to sell product.
- Provided content for Instagram and website by photographing and writing descriptions for all products.
- Created graphic design content such as banners and call-to-action images for Instagram, website, and email use.

Boiling Point Restaurant

Assistant Manager | September 2014 - December 2016 Supervisor | December 2013 - December 2016 Trainer | March 2015 - December 2016 Server, Bobartender, Cook | June 2012 - December 2016

- Ran the restaurant efficiently by managing employees' hours and duties according to its peak and slow hours.
- Strong communication and people skills helped solve internal and external problems under stressful conditions.



© 408.529.2410 https://jessicacheng.design

EDUCATION

Bloc

December 2018 - March 2020 UI/UX (Designer Track) Certification

Otis College of Art and Design August 2009 - May 2013 B.F.A. Product Design

SKILLS

Computer Programs

- Adobe Creative Suite [AE, ID, IL, LR, and PS]
- Microsoft Word [Excel, Powerpoint, and Word]
- Rhino [3-D and V-Ray]

Graphic Design

- Branding
- Logo Making
- Presentations
- Print
- Storytelling

Product Design

- Ceramics
- Hand Renderings [Sketching and Computer]
- Pattern Making
- Sewing [Hand and Machine]
- Technical Packages
- Weaving
- Welding
- Woodworking

UI/UX Design

- Atom
- Basic HTML and CSS
- Figma and InVision
- GitHub
- Preference Testing
- Prototyping
- Research
- Usability Testing
- Wireframing

Languages

- English
- Mandarin Chinese

AWARDS

Almaden Art and Wine Festival 2009

Steve Boyer Designs

Production Intern | June 2013 - September 2013

- Collaborated with a design team to create a phone app, Colorfields, for the iGlow event.
- Enhanced UX design by preparing wire frames, maps, information and navigational architecture, and UI design.

Anthropologie

Display Intern | June 2012 - August 2012

• Worked with display team to decorate window displays and created props, furniture, and other apparatuses to market company's clothing and products.



© 408.529.2410

https://jessicacheng.design